Calvin Tomkins Papers
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series IV: Books, 1968-1998
  - Subseries IV.D:Duchamp: A Biography, 1953-1998
    - Duchamp Miscellaneous, Bibliographies and bibliographical notes on Duchamp from various sources, expense report and receipts from 1964, eight-page book proposal for the biography. (Box 58, Folder IV.D.33)
    - Marcel Duchamp at the Palazzo Grassi, Press kit, reviews of catalogue and exhibit held in Venice, 1993. (Box 58, Folder IV.D.34)
    - Duchamp - Interviews (Unpublished), 1953; Photocopy of unpublished interview transcript between Duchamp, Sydney Janis, and others.. (Box 58, Folder IV.D.35)
    - Photos, Photographs, transparencies, and negatives of Duchamp and his artworks, postcards and ephemera from the book publication, drafts of cover design. Most photographs are labeled and attributed, some appear to be original or contemporary duplicate prints. (Box 58, Folder IV.D.36)
    - Photos, Photographs, transparencies, photocopies of Duchamp and his artworks (particularly early drawings), some photographs unlabeled and unattributed and may be original. (Box 58, Folder IV.D.37)
    - Duchamp Post-Mortem, 1972-2000; Exhibition reviews, essays, news clippings and articles on Duchamp, ephemera. (Box 58, Folder IV.D.38)
    - Duchamp Post-Mortem, 1973-1991; News clippings, ephemera, articles. (Box 58, Folder IV.D.39)
    - Duchamp Post-Mortem, 1985-1993; Includes photocopy of entire catalogue to exhibition The Marcel Duchamp Exhibition, 9/20-10/16/1985, The Art Museum at Florida International University. (Box 59, Folder IV.D.40)
    - Duchamp - Articles About, 1960-1995; Articles, news clippings, and ephemera. (Box 59, Folder IV.D.41)
    - Duchamp - Articles About, 1968-1989 (Box 59, Folder IV.D.42)
    - Duchamp - Articles About, 1966-1997 (Box 59, Folder IV.D.43)
    - Naumann - Walter Pach (Letters) - Draft, Photocopy of draft typescript, by Francis Naumann, on the correspondence between Pach and Duchamp, includes photocopies of original letters from the Archives of American Art. (Box 59, Folder IV.D.44)
    - Bessie Breuer, Unpublished Autobiographical MS, Photocopy of 56-page typescript. (Box 59, Folder IV.D.45)
    - Duchamp Interview Questions & Book List, Lists of book party invitees and recipients of complimentary copies, documents regarding the authentication of an early Duchamp drawing, questions for CT from book talk at the Whitney Museum. (Box 59, Folder IV.D.46)
    - Brancusi - Letters from MD, Photocopies of correspondence between Constantin Brancusi and Duchamp. (Box 59, Folder IV.D.47)
    - The Supermale by Alfred Jarry, Photocopies of original French text and English translation. (Box 59, Folder IV.D.48)
    - Duchamp Photos - World Rights, 1998; Permission forms, invoices, receipts and correspondence regarding images. (Box 59, Folder IV.D.49)
    - Duchamp - Permissions, 1996; Permission forms, invoices, receipts and correspondence regarding images. (Box 59, Folder IV.D.50)
    - Loose Book Photographs, Photographs, transparencies and photocopies of images, most labeled, many with editorial comments.; Items in this and the following folders were loose in the original Duchamp files. (Box 60, Folder IV.D.51)
    - Loose Book Photographs (Box 60, Folder IV.D.52)
    - Loose Book Photographs (Box 60, Folder IV.D.53)
    - Loose Book Photographs (Box 60, Folder IV.D.54)
    - Loose Book Photographs (Box 60, Folder IV.D.55)
    - MD Photos - Correspondence, 1996; Correspondence from and to CT and DK concerning rights and reproductions, list of captions and credits for images included in book. (Box 60, Folder IV.D.56)
    - Duchamp - Correspondence, 1995-1996; Reader responses, communications involving critical responses, sent and received research correspondence and letters from other writers and researchers, correspondence between CT, Jacqueline Matisse Monnier and Francis Naumann, CT's suggested changes to book layout, correspondence between CT's agent Andrew Wylie and the book's editor, Jack MacRae of Henry Holt 1 TLS facsimile Claes Oldenburg-CT (7/29/1996) [re: Duchamp influence] 1 ALS facsimile Pontus Hulten-CT (4/26/1996) [re:Etant donns]. (Box 60, Folder IV.D.57)
    - Duchamp - Correspondence, 1993-1995; Multiple correspondence among Teeny Duchamp, Jacqueline Matisse Monnier, Francis Naumann, and CT and DK, general research correspondence. 1 TLS facsimile Jacqueline Matisse Monnier-CT (12/20/1995) [re: announcement of the passing of Teeny Duchamp at "6:25 p.m."]. (Box 60, Folder IV.D.58)
    - Duchamp - Correspondence, 1989-1993; Correspondence from Teeny Duchamp, Jacqueline Matisse Monnier, Francis Naumann, general research correspondence. (Box 60, Folder IV.D.59)
    - Duchamp - Correspondence, 1964-1989; Correspondence from research for CT's original Profile on Duchamp including two photocopies of letters from Duchamp to CT (12/8/1964 and 5/10/1966), general research correspondence. 1 TLS Richard Hamilton-CT [4/5/1964) [re: agreement to be interviewed for Profile] 1 TLS Richard Hamilton-CT (2/19/1989) [re: refusal to be interviewed for book]. (Box 61, Folder IV.D.60)
    - Loose Photocopies, Photocopies of pictures and photographs collected for research or for consideration for use in book. Many from an unknown archival collection, images are paired with printouts of their catalogue records. (Box 61, Folder IV.D.61)
    - Loose Photocopies (Box 61, Folder IV.D.62)
    - "MD Vox" Research Binder, Transcripts and photocopies of published and unpublished interviews with Duchamp, includes complete transcript of CT's 1964 interview. (Box 61, Folder IV.D.63)
    - "MD Vox" Research Binder (Box 61, Folder IV.D.64)
    - "Chromo" Research Binder, Chronological notes on Duchamp's life with month-by-month entries during critical periods. (Box 61, Folder IV.D.65)
    - Untitled Research Binder, Binder of notes and transcript extracts of interviews conducted specifically for the book and for past articles, in tabbed sections by decade of Duchamp's life. (Box 61, Folder IV.D.66)
    - Untitled Research Binder, Further notes and transcript extracts, includes draft typescript of the New York Times obituary for Teeny Duchamp and correspondence from Paul Matisse enclosing the text of his eulogy for his mother given at her memorial, 1995. (Box 61, Folder IV.D.67)
    - Marcel Duchamp - Katherine Dreier Correspondence, Four bound volumes (labeled #1-#4) of photocopies of the entire collection of Duchamp-Dreier correspondence and related material from the Katherine S. Dreier Papers, Yale University Library, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library. Correspondence dates from 1917-1952. (Box 91, Folder IV.D.68*)
    - Marcel Duchamp - Katharine Kuh Correspondence, One bound volume (labeled #5) of photocopies of the Duchamp-Kuh correspondence from the Katharine Kuh Papers, Yale University Library, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library. Correspondence dates from 1948-1961. (Box 91, Folder IV.D.69*)
  - Subseries IV.E: Book Photographs
    This series contains photographs, negatives, and transparencies collected and used in the books Living Well is the Best Revenge,The Scene: Reports on Post-Modern Art,Off the Wall: Robert Rauschenberg and the Art World of Our Time, and Duchamp: A Biography. The individual folders note if the images are labeled or unlabeled and other particular features.
    For more photographs and images from the biography of Duchamp, see folders IV.D.51-55, 61-62, for information on the provenance and subject of the images of Duchamp and Rauschenberg, see folders IV.D.5-51, IV.D.56 and IV.C.61
    - 8x10" and 9x12" Photographs, 30 images of Rauschenberg, the Merce Cunningham Dance Company, and numerous other luminaries of the art world including Leo Castelli and his stable of artists and the European "Artists in Exile" of World War II, with some exhibition photos. (Box 92, Item IV.E.1*)
    - 12x16" Photographs, 17 images, all by Ugo Mules and obtained from him, of Rauschenberg, Duchamp, and other artists and artworks of the 1960s including Andy Warhol, George Segal, Claes Oldenburg, Roy Lichtenstein, and others. Photographs are unlabeled. (Box 92, Item IV.E.2*)
    - Photographs and Negatives from The Scene, Includes two-page photocopied summary of interview with James Rosenquist, 6/23/1978, 8x10" color transparency of Rauschenberg painting, 13 4x5" negatives of same images found in IV.E.1, 11x15" author photograph of CT, 30 8x10" and smaller images, most with editing marks, and 14 8x10" and smaller negatives. (Box 92, Item IV.E.3*)
    - Negatives from Living Well Is the Best Revenge, Label on original box stated that these are negatives of "all" the photographs used in the book. Approximately 71 images of various sizes and most with black paper and red tape cropping. The tape has caused many images to become stuck to one another. (Box 92, Item IV.E.4*)
- Series V: Audio Recordings, 1962-2006
  The basis of all of Tomkins' major writings for The New Yorker was in-person interviews with his subjects. Therefore, the four open reels and 494 cassette audio recordings contained in this series constitute perhaps the most important original, unique materials of the entire collection. Nonetheless, until the late 1980s, Tomkins did not regularly record his interviews and instead trusted to his note-taking and memory for reconstruction of conversations. Yet the earliest recordings, of Jean Tinguely (1962), Marcel Duchamp (1964), and R. Buckminster Fuller (1965), testify to Tomkins' consciousness of the importance of those individuals. Even as Tomkins recorded the interviews, he rarely made complete transcripts of them, preferring to summarize the interviews in his research binders while quoting only key paragraphs and statements by his subjects. When, in later years, full transcripts do exist, they were usually written by Dodie Kazanjian, who accompanied and aided Tomkins in his research and interviews.
  The audio recordings were received loosely grouped by subject and date. They have been rearranged here in strict chronological order. Interviews for different articles may overlap in time. The recordings are inconsistently labeled; many are missing dates, full names (some names have been added in brackets,) or reference to which particular person or article they were recorded for. Most tapes lack any indication also as to how long they are or how much of the tape they take up. Researchers should first consult the interview binders in Series II.B before asking to consult the actual audio recordings. Occasional tapes record interviews for Art World reviews or smaller articles.
  The four open reel audio recordings in the collection are various brands and types but all are " width on 7" reels. V.2 and V.3 have been digitally preserved and CD copies are available.
  - Jean Tinguely, ca. 1962; Undated (Box 63, Reel V.1)
    3 rpm, Scotch brand no. 111-12, 1200 feet.
  - Marcel Duchamp, ca. 1964; Undated; This recording has been preserved. In addition to the original, a CD-R use copy now exists. (Box 63, Reel V.2)
    Speed unknown, Scotch Brand "Tartan Series" no. 144-2400, 2400 feet. This recording has been preserved. In addition to the original, a CD-R use copy now exists.
  - Marcel Duchamp, 3/23/1964; , 3/26/1964; Complete transcripts for the March 1964 interviews and partial transcripts of other interviews can be found in folders IV.D.29 and IV.D.63; This recording has been preserved. In addition to the original, a CD-R use copy now exists. (Box 63, Reel V.3)
    Monophonic, 3 rpm, Audio devices, Inc. Audiotape brand Type 1251, 1200 feet.
  - "Duchamp 1", 3/1964; Duplicate of reel "Duchamp - Mar. 1964" Side A: "-to 550 on tape 1, side A" Side B: "-to end of side A" (Box 64, Cassette V.4)
    Denon DX1/1990
  - "Duchamp 2", 3/1964; Duplicate of reel "Duchamp - Mar. '64" Side A: "-to 550 on Tape 1 side B" Side B: "-to end of side B" (Box 64, Cassette V.5)
  - "Marcel Duchamp 3", 3/1964; Duplicate of reel "Duchamp 2nd invu 1964" Side A: "side one" Side B: "side one (cont.)" (Box 64, Cassette V.6)
  - "Duchamp 4", 3/1964; Duplicate of reel. "Duchamp - Mar. 1964 2nd invu" Side A: "to end of side A" Side B: "Side B" (Box 64, Cassette V.7)
  - "Duchamp 5", 3/1964; Possible duplicate of reel. (Box 64, Cassette V.8)
    Sony HF90
  - R. Buckminster Fuller, 8/1965; Note in box reads "Bucky Fuller/Bear Island/Aug. 1965 (3)" (Box 63, Reel V.9)
    3 rpm, Soundcraft brand no. S-12, 1200 feet.
  - Duchamp - TV Interviews, n.d.; "Duchamp - TV invus - J.M. Drot, J.J. Sweeney" (Box 64, Cassette V.10)
    Supertape HD-90
  - Paul Matisse, 8/1988 (Box 64, Cassette V.11)
    Maxell UR90
  - Beatrice Wood, 8/20/1988; "(Duchamp)" (Box 64, Cassette V.12)
  - John Cage on Duchamp, 2/17/1989 (Box 64, Cassette V.13)
  - Yo Sermayer, 9/1989 (Box 64, Cassette V.14)
  - Kay Boyle, 1/11/1990; "(on Duchamp)" (Box 64, Cassette V.15)
  - [Walter] Hopps Houston, 1/6/1990 (Box 64, Cassette V.16)
  - [Walter] Hopps (Bio Tape One), 11/7/1990; "000-043 - end of 11/6/1990; invu in 20th Cent. Galleries; 045- Bio" (Box 64, Cassette V.17)
  - [Walter] Hopps Bio tape Two, 11/7/1990 (Box 64, Cassette V.18)
  - [Walter] Hopps (Bio Tape Three), 11/8/1990 (Box 64, Cassette V.19)
  - [Walter] Hopps (Bio Tape Four), 11/8/1990 (Box 64, Cassette V.20)
  - [Walter] Hopps Bio Tape Five, 11/9/1990 (Box 64, Cassette V.21)
  - [Walter] Hopps (#1), 11/10/1990 (Box 64, Cassette V.22)
  - [Walter] Hopps, 11/10/1990 (Box 65, Cassette V.23)
  - Hopps Invus - Demetrion - Frailin - Hopper, ca. 1990; Side A: "Jim Demetrion" Side B: "Frank Frailin (to 289); Saul Steinberg (to 265); Dennis Hopper (370-712)" (Box 65, Cassette V.24)
    Denon HD8/1990
  - Hopps Invus - Dennis Hopper - Tom Leavitt..., ca. 1990; Side A: "Dennis Hopper (cont.) (000-112); Tom Leavitt (113-330)" Side B: "Hopps - 11/4/1990 (at Carlyle) - MacAlys in Calif. & Texas" (Box 65, Cassette V.25)
    Fuji DR90
  - Irving Blum (on Hopps); Walter Hopps, ca. 1990; Side A: Irving Blum Side B: "Blum - to 170; (172) Walter Hopps on American Imagism" (Box 65, Cassette V.26)
  - Henry Wolf, n.d.; "Barbara & Leo" marked on cassette. (Box 65, Cassette V.27)
    Fuji DR-I 90
  - Shirley Blum, 12/13/1990 (Box 65, Cassette V.28)
    Maxell UDS-II 90
  - [Walter] Hopps (1), 12/15/1990 (Box 65, Cassette V.29)
  - [Walter] Hopps (2), 12/15/1990 (Box 65, Cassette V.30)
  - [Walter] Hopps #2, 3/10/1991 (Box 65, Cassette V.31)
  - [Walter] Hopps, 3/10/1991 (Box 65, Cassette V.32)
  - Jasper Johns, 3/19/1991 (Box 65, Cassette V.33)
  - Robert Motherwell, 5/10/1991; "Motherwell on Duchamp" (Box 65, Cassette V.34)
    Sony Metal-SR (90 minutes)
  - [Walter] Hopps, ca. 1990 (Box 65, Cassette V.35)
  - [Walter] Hopps - Telephone invus (post-Houston), ca. 1990 (Box 65, Cassette V.36)
  - Brenda Richardson (Box 65, Cassette V.37)
  - Richard Rogers, 3/26/1993 (Box 65, Cassette V.38)
    TDK HF90
  - Matta - I, 3/29/1993 (Box 65, Cassette V.39)
    TDK D90
  - Matta - II, 3/31/1993 (Box 65, Cassette V.40)
  - Matta - III, 4/1/1993 (Box 66, Cassette V.41)
  - Renzo Piano - 1, ca. 1994 (Box 66, Cassette V.42)
  - Renzo Piano, ca. 1994 (Box 66, Cassette V.43)
  - Charles Ray, ca. 1995; Container unlabeled. (Box 66, Cassette V.44)
    Sony HF 90
  - Charles Ray, ca. 1995; Container unlabeled. (Box 66, Cassette V.45)
  - Charles Ray, 4/20/1995; Container unlabeled. (Box 66, Cassette V.46)
  - [Albert] York, ca. 1995 (Box 66, Cassette V.47)
  - [Albert] York, ca. 1995 (Box 66, Cassette V.48)
  - [Albert] York II, ca. 1995 (Box 66, Cassette V.49)
  - [Albert] York III, ca. 1995 (Box 66, Cassette V.50)
  - Philip Johnson, 8/18/1995 (Box 66, Cassette V.51)
  - Oldenburg, 9/1995; Uncertain whether Claes or Richard Oldenburg (Box 66, Cassette V.52)
  - [Dan] Kiley A, ca. 1995; Cassette marked "Dan & Ann" (Box 66, Cassette V.53)
  - [Dan] Kiley (B), ca. 1995 (Box 66, Cassette V.54)
  - [Dan] Kiley C, ca. 1995 (Box 66, Cassette V.55)
  - [Dan] Kiley II, ca. 1995; Cassette marked "Kiley III Kimn...el house" (Box 66, Cassette V.56)
  - [Dan] Kiley 4, ca. 1995; Cassette marked: "Kiley 4" struck out and replaced with "Schwartz" (Box 66, Cassette V.57)
  - [Dan] Kiley 5, ca. 1995; Cassette marked: "Kiley 5" struck out and replaced with "Richard Meier" (Box 66, Cassette V.58)
  - [Dan] Kiley VI, ca. 1995; Cassette marked: "Kiley VI" struck out and replaced with "Jack Robertson" (Box 66, Cassette V.59)
  - [Jeff] Koons, 3/22/1996 (Box 67, Cassette V.60)
    TDK SA90
  - Bill Rubin on Picasso & Portraiture, 3/22/1996 (Box 67, Cassette V.61)
  - Nicole Eisenman, 3/25/1996 (Box 67, Cassette V.62)
  - Carter Brown, 3/28/1996 (Box 67, Cassette V.63)
  - Nicole Eisenman, 4/15-4/16/1996 (Box 67, Cassette V.64)
  - Kusama, 10/1996 (Box 67, Cassette V.65)
  - Si Newhouse, n.d.; Side A: "Si Newhouse/Ben Heller" Side B: "Kirk Varnedoe/Alana Heiss" (Box 67, Cassette V.66)
  - Milton Wexeler/Gehry, 3/22/1997; Side B: "(Defective tape - slow); Ron Davis house; Norton Simon (110-" Cassette marked: "Milton --Frank (B); Gehry 3/22 (Defective)" (Box 67, Cassette V.67)
  - Frank Gehry, 3/22/1997; Side A: "On Norton Simon; On Disney Hall" Side B: "Problem with IRS; Bio - grandparents & parents - Toronto - Timmens - back to Toronto - move to LA" (Box 67, Cassette V.68)
  - [Frank] Gehry, 3/23/1997; Side A: "Lillian Hellman Story (0-168) (Blank)" Side B: "(Blank)" (Box 67, Cassette V.69)
  - [Frank] Gehry, 3/23/1997; Side A: "0-175 Bio; Early years in LA - meeting Anita - night school at USC; (tape ends at 175)" Cassette marked "(background II)" (Box 67, Cassette V.70)
  - [Frank] Gehry (Bio 1), 3/24/1997; Side A: "Canada - Early years LA" Side B: "School (night); USC" (Box 67, Cassette V.71)
  - [Frank] Gehry (Bio 2), 3/24/1997; Side A: "Army Service 0-200; Harvard 200-400; Gruen 400-630" Side B: "Europe 0-; Office" (Box 67, Cassette V.72)
    Maxell XL II-S 90
  - [Frank] Gehry - 1, ca. 1997 (Box 67, Cassette V.73)
  - [Frank] Gehry - 2, ca. 1997 (Box 67, Cassette V.74)
  - [Frank] Gehry - 3, ca. 1997 (Box 67, Cassette V.75)
  - [Frank] Gehry - 4, ca. 1997 (Box 67, Cassette V.76)
  - Gehry Bilbao (1), ca. 1997 (Box 67, Cassette V.77)
  - Gehry Bilbao (2), ca. 1997 (Box 67, Cassette V.78)
  - Gehry Bilbao (3), ca. 1997 (Box 67, Cassette V.79)
  - TELLUS, The Audio Cassette Magazine #21, n.d.; "Audio by Visual Artists" (Box 68, Cassette V.80)
  - Soundings - Robert Rauschenberg, 6/14/1998; BBC radio program including comments by CT (Box 68, Cassette V.81)
    TDK AR100
  - Rauschenberg (1), n.d. (Box 68, Cassette V.82)
  - Rauschenberg (2), n.d. (Box 68, Cassette V.83)
  - Rauschenberg (3), n.d. (Box 68, Cassette V.84)
  - Philippe Petit (1), 9/27/1998 (Box 68, Cassette V.85)
  - Philippe Petit (2), 9/27/1998 (Box 68, Cassette V.86)
  - Susan Hartnett, 9/30/1998 (Box 68, Cassette V.87)
    Fuji DR-I 60
  - Philippe Petit (3), 10/5/1998 (Box 68, Cassette V.88)
  - Philippe Petit (4), 10/5/1998 (Box 68, Cassette V.89)
  - Philippe Petit (5), 10/18/1998 (Box 68, Cassette V.90)
  - Philippe Petit (6), 10/18/1998 (Box 68, Cassette V.91)
  - Terry Winters, 11/21/1998 (Box 68, Cassette V.92)
  - Ileana [Sonnabend] & Antonio, 12/31/1998 (Box 68, Cassette V.93)
  - PP Canyon (1), 2/13/1999 (Box 68, Cassette V.94)
  - PP Canyon (2), ca. 1999 (Box 68, Cassette V.95)
  - PP Canyon (3), 2/13/1999 (Box 68, Cassette V.96)
  - PP Canyon (4), 2/14/1999 (Box 68, Cassette V.97)
  - Candida Smith, 5/25/1999; Cassette marked: "Candida at Storm King 5/30" and "Candida on David Smith" (Box 68, Cassette V.98)
  - Joo - Chiat, 5/26/1999; Side A: "Jay Chiat (to 430); Michael Joo" Side B: "Michael Joo 5/26" (Box 68, Cassette V.99)
    Sony CD-IT 90
  - Marco Piere White; Norman Rosenthal - Alex James, 6/8/1999; Side A: "Marco Piere White (to 320); Norman Rosenthal (to end)" Side B: "Norman Rosenthal (to 070); Alex James at Mirabelle; On Damien's boat; warning notice re: fireworks" (Box 69, Cassette V.100)
    Sony UX 90
  - Jasper Johns, 8/29-8/30/1999; "On Leo Castelli" (Box 69, Cassette V.101)
  - Jasper Johns, n.d. (Box 69, Cassette V.102)
  - Damien [Hirst], ca. 1999 (Box 69, Cassette V.103)
    Sony HiFi 90
  - (1) Damien [Hirst], Jude, ca. 1999 (Box 69, Cassette V.104)
  - (2) Moynahan, Dunphy, ca. 1999; "2" crossed out; A: Moynahan, B: Dunphy (Box 69, Cassette V.105)
  - (3) [Rachel] Whiteread, ca. 1999 (Box 69, Cassette V.106)
  - (4) Craig - Martin, ca. 1999 (Box 69, Cassette V.107)
  - Damien [Hirst], ca. 1999 (Box 69, Cassette V.108)
  - Damien - Train - Devon 1, ca. 1999 (Box 69, Cassette V.109)
  - Sarah Lucas; Hugh Allen, ca. 1999; Side A: "Sarah Lucas (to 410); Hugh Allen (410 to end)" Side B: "Hugh Allen" (Box 69, Cassette V.110)
  - Hugh Allen (cont.); Gordon Burns, ca. 1999; Side A: "Hugh Allen (to 208); Gordon Burns (208-end)" Side B: "Gordon Burns (to 325)" (Box 69, Cassette V.111)
  - Joplins, ca. 1999 (Box 69, Cassette V.112)
  - Ileana Sonnabend, 9/30/1999; "Ileana S. at Da Silvano, with Antonio Homem." (Box 69, Cassette V.113)
  - Cindy Sherman (1), 10/26/1999 (Box 69, Cassette V.114)
  - Cindy Sherman (2), 11/2/1999 (Box 69, Cassette V.115)
  - Peter Galassi, 11/4/1999; "@MoMA" (Box 69, Cassette V.116)
  - Helene Winer, 11/10/1999 (Box 69, Cassette V.117)
  - Laurie Simmons, 11/17/1999 (Box 70, Cassette V.118)
  - Cindy Sherman (3), 11/19/1999 (Box 70, Cassette V.119)
  - Robert Longo, 11/29/1999 (Box 70, Cassette V.120)
  - Susan Jennings, 12/1/1999 (Box 70, Cassette V.121)
  - Elizabeth Leite, 12/4/1999; "(Cindy Sherman's Sister)" (Box 70, Cassette V.122)
  - Linda Cathcart, 12/9/1999 (Box 70, Cassette V.123)
  - Janelle Reiring, 12/22/1999 (Box 70, Cassette V.124)
  - Charles Clough, 12/27/1999 (Box 70, Cassette V.125)
  - Bob Shermand & John Sherman; Eric Bogosian, 1/24-1/25/2000 (Box 70, Cassette V.126)
  - Ingrid Sischy, 1/26/2000 (Box 70, Cassette V.127)
  - John McEnroe, 2/9/2000 (Box 70, Cassette V.128)
  - Cindy Sherman #4, 2/10/2000 (Box 70, Cassette V.129)
  - Cindy 5; Cindy 6, 2/13/2000; "Cindy 5 - to A175; Cindy 6 (A175 - end)" (Box 70, Cassette V.130)
  - Bill T. Jones; Carol Kane; Nancy Dwyer, 2/18-2/22/2000 (Box 70, Cassette V.131)
  - John McEnroe, Sr., 2/23/2000 (Box 70, Cassette V.132)
  - Cindy #6, 3/8/2000 (Box 70, Cassette V.133)
  - McEnroe (2), 3/15/2000 (Box 70, Cassette V.134)
  - Tony Palafox, 4/15/2000 (Box 70, Cassette V.135)
  - Brian Hunt, 4/19/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.136)
  - McEnroe (3), 4/24/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.137)
  - Eugene Scott, 4/25/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.138)
  - McEnroe (4)Richmond, 4/28-4/29/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.139)
  - McEnroe 4-B, 4/30/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.140)
  - Eric Fischl/April Gornik, 5/3/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.141)
  - Patty Smyth McEnroe, 5/9/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.142)
  - McEnroe 5, 5/25/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.143)
  - Mark McEnroe/Mary Carillo, 5/30-6/13/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.144)
  - McEnroe - Tiebreaker, 6/23/2000; Cassette marked: "McEnroe 6" (Box 71, Cassette V.145)
  - Larry Salander - NBC TV Wimbledon; Peter Fleming, 7/2/2000; Side A: "Larry Salander on JM - to 128; (130- ) NBC TV from Wimbledon, JM & Borg on 1980 final" Side B: Peter Fleming (Box 71, Cassette V.146)
  - McEnroe (Santander), 7/23/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.147)
  - Peter Galassi, 9/15/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.148)
  - Andreas Gursky I, 10/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.149)
  - Gursky I (cont.); Gursky I & II, 10/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.150)
  - Gursky II & III, ca. 2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.151)
  - Gursky III, ca. 2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.152)
  - Bernd & Hilla Becker, 10/6/2000 (Box 71, Cassette V.153)
  - Bernd & Hilla Becker (2), 10/6/2000 (Box 72, Cassette V.154)
  - Thomas Ruff, 10/6/2000 (Box 72, Cassette V.155)
  - Thomas Demand, 10/9/2000 (Box 72, Cassette V.156)
  - [Andreas] Gursky (1), 10/10/2000 (Box 72, Cassette V.157)
  - Gursky (2), 10/10/2000 (Box 72, Cassette V.158)
  - Gursky (3), 10/10/2000 (Box 72, Cassette V.159)
  - Gursky (4), 11/2/2000 (Box 72, Cassette V.160)